<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://biplabdutta.com.np/</id><title>Biplab Dutta</title><subtitle>My name is Biplab Dutta. I am from Nepal working as a mobile application developer (native Android and Flutter).</subtitle> <updated>2022-10-15T18:00:18+05:45</updated> <author> <name>Biplab Dutta</name> <uri>https://biplabdutta.com.np/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://biplabdutta.com.np/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="https://biplabdutta.com.np/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2022 Biplab Dutta </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>A deep dive into unit testing in Flutter 🧪</title><link href="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/unit-test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A deep dive into unit testing in Flutter 🧪" /><published>2022-08-20T09:00:00+05:45</published> <updated>2022-10-09T19:44:16+05:45</updated> <id>https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/unit-test/</id> <content src="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/unit-test/" /> <author> <name>Biplab</name> </author> <category term="flutter" /> <summary> Testing code is an important task for a developer that helps us in ensuring that our code works as expected. Testing is an important task that should not be given the least priority or be neglected. Many companies seeking for a software developer candidate look for those who can perform testing effectively. Many open-source projects don’t prefer to merge contributions for which tests are not in... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Theme Switching &amp; Persisting in Flutter using cubits and Stream</title><link href="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/theme-switching/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Theme Switching &amp; Persisting in Flutter using cubits and Stream" /><published>2022-06-08T18:00:00+05:45</published> <updated>2022-10-09T19:44:16+05:45</updated> <id>https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/theme-switching/</id> <content src="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/theme-switching/" /> <author> <name>Biplab</name> </author> <category term="flutter" /> <summary> Every mobile app user prefers having an option to choose between multiple themes. Having decent themes available is also very crucial in enhancing the user experience. So, how can we do it effectively in Flutter? How can we have different configs set for each theme? This article ensures that you get a proper understanding of it and I’ll also talk a bit regarding Stream in Dart. Table of Conte... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Product Flavors in Flutter—Create admin and non-admin apps with distinct UI with a single codebase</title><link href="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/product-flavors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Product Flavors in Flutter—Create admin and non-admin apps with distinct UI with a single codebase" /><published>2022-05-21T16:00:00+05:45</published> <updated>2022-10-09T19:44:16+05:45</updated> <id>https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/product-flavors/</id> <content src="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/product-flavors/" /> <author> <name>Biplab</name> </author> <category term="flutter" /> <summary> Have you ever wondered how some mobile applications have admin and non-admin variants? The admin app has different UIs than the non-admin ones. Or have you seen some apps on the Play Store or App Store with premium and freemium versions? So, how do developers actually do it? How do they create multiple variants of the same project? Do they manage multiple codebases? Is there one team responsibl... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Form Validation in Flutter using flutter_bloc and Functional Programming (Either)—A Proper Way</title><link href="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/form-validation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Form Validation in Flutter using flutter_bloc and Functional Programming (Either)—A Proper Way" /><published>2022-05-15T15:00:00+05:45</published> <updated>2022-10-09T19:44:16+05:45</updated> <id>https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/form-validation/</id> <content src="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/form-validation/" /> <author> <name>Biplab</name> </author> <category term="flutter" /> <summary> Dealing with forms is a very common task that we encounter as mobile application developers. With forms come form validation. It is necessary to show relevant warnings to the users when they don’t fill-up the form as they were supposed to. In order to do so, we need to write certain validation logic. However, the declarative UI approach in flutter results in many developers writing their valida... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>A Taste of Reactive Programming in Flutter with RxDart and flutter_bloc</title><link href="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/reactive-programming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Taste of Reactive Programming in Flutter with RxDart and flutter_bloc" /><published>2022-05-07T17:00:00+05:45</published> <updated>2022-10-09T19:44:16+05:45</updated> <id>https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/reactive-programming/</id> <content src="https://biplabdutta.com.np/posts/reactive-programming/" /> <author> <name>Biplab</name> </author> <category term="flutter" /> <summary> When it comes to reactive programming, not many developers, especially junior developers feel comfortable with it. The base for reactive programming in Dart is Stream, a type in dart used to represent an asynchronous sequence of data. In this article, we will learn about what streams are, when to use them, and how to use them by building a simple flutter application and bringing everything into... </summary> </entry> </feed>
